Guide to the F. Herbert Bormann Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Speeches and writings, 1950-2009; Series IV
  - Writings
    - Nitrogen, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - "Origin of Small Watershed Technique for the Study of Ecosystems", 1997 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Outline for mineral weathering papers, 1993-09-10 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Peopling of the Americas; intertidal zone, 2004 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Personal writings, 2007-2008, undated (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Pin Cherry
      - Editing comments and revisions, 1999-2003 (Box 16, Folder 11-12)
      - Fahey manuscript, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - Outline and drafts, 1994-2001 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Potential publications, 1997-2005 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Recent work on Branford Supply Pond, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Red pine, 2003 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Redesigning the American Lawn
      - Edits, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 18)
      - Second edition, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Redundancy and stability of ecosystems, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - "Respect for Nature", 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Scientific gardening inventions, 1985 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Statements before legislative bodies, 1966-1996 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - The Statistical Efficiency of Plot Size and Shape in Forest Ecology (MA Thesis), 1950 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - "Subtraction by Multiplication: Population, Technology, and the Diminished Man.", Circa 1969-1971 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Suburban land development, 2002-07 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Suburban land development and the hydrologic cycle, 1999-2002 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Supply Pond, 1998-2006 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - Tree poster, 2006 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Understanding how nature works, 2007-2008 (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - University of Vermont, 2002 (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Untitled foreword, Undated (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - "On the Whole Being Greater Than the Sum of its Parts", 2005 (Box 16, Folder 33)
    - Work with Gene E. Likens, 1995-2000 (Box 16, Folder 34)
- Born digital files, 1984-2006; Series V
  Closed until processed.
  This series consists of seventeen 5.25 inch floppy disks, nine 3.5 inch floppy disks, one CD-R, and one CD-RW. Labels on the disks suggest that the contents include text of speeches and writings, correspondence such as student recommendations, teaching materials, Bormann's curriculum vitae and other professional biographical materials, and backup/boot files for different software and operating systems.
  - Drive B, 2015-M-065-0001; 1 (Box 20)
  - FH Bormann's copy Recommendation disk 12/18/86, 2015-M-065-0002; 1 (Box 20)
  - Working disk- June 87, 2015-M-065-0003; 1 (Box 20)
  - Advanced Ecology, 2015-M-065-0004; 1 (Box 20)
  - Herb's Text #1, 2015-M-065-0005; 1 (Box 20)
  - 84-85 Home Herb's Text #2, 2015-M-065-0006; 1 (Box 20)
  - 85 Herb's Text 3, 2015-M-065-0007; 1 (Box 20)
  - Herb's 4 1986, 2015-M-065-0008; 1 (Box 20)
  - Herb 1987, 2015-M-065-0009; 1 (Box 20)
  - Herb's Wordstar Drive a: Lettrix, 2015-M-065-0010; 1 (Box 21)
  - No Good Formatted Working disk, 2015-M-065-0011; 1 (Box 21)
  - Herb's Wordstar backup, 2015-M-065-0012; 1 (Box 21)
  - Card filer, 2015-M-065-0013; 1 (Box 21)
  - French, 2015-M-065-0014; 1 (Box 21)
  - DOS Back up, 2015-M-065-0015; 1 (Box 21)
  - Card file, Wordstar Backup copy, 2015-M-065-0016; 1 (Box 21)
  - LETTRIX source Put in B: at start up May 85, 2015-M-065-0017; 1 (Box 21)
  - 1987 save Get A:> A:> edit1987SAVE, 2015-M-065-0018; 1 (Reel 19)
  - Autobiography, 2015-M-065-0019; 1 (Reel 19)
  - >misc >oldrecs >address >work87 edit dir Press X edit misc, 2015-M-065-0020; 1 (Reel 19)
  - Formatted Herb's backup disk #1 1988- files By sub directory, 2015-M-065-0021; 1 (Reel 19)
  - Formatted on Herb's laptop Recs, 2015-M-065-0022; 1 (Reel 19)
  - \1984 save 42 files \1984-1985 59 files 1984 Edit dir Press X edit 1984SAVE edit 1984-1985, 2015-M-065-0023; 1 (Reel 19)
  - \1985save \1986save A:> edit 1985save edit 1986save, 2015-M-065-0024; 1 (Reel 19)
  - Aug. 27 Copied from C drive Students, letters, lectures, Hubbrook, committees, personal, misc. No more space. edit dir Press X, 2015-M-065-0025; 1 (Reel 19)
  - Herb's Boot Disk Copy of personnel dir, 2015-M-065-0026; 1 (Reel 19)
  - Herb Bormann SBBG talk 2/22/06, 2015-M-065-0027; 1 (Box 22)
  - F H Bormann CV & Files SAVE, 2015-M-065-0028; 1 (Box 23)